Guide to Montana Public Service Commission, Utilities Division records 1913-1986
Montana Historical Society
- Water Utilities, 1916-1969
  - Annual Reports
    - Neihart Water Company (municipal), 1951, 1961-1969 (Box-folder 16 / 22)
    - North Gardiner: Scott Water Plant (includes rate schedule, 1924), 1939-1953 (Box-folder 17 / 1)
    - North Gardiner: Bigelow Water Company, 1954-1968 (Box-folder 17 / 2)
    - Noxon Water Association / Community Gravity Water Company (municipal; includes rate schedule, 1932), 1954-1968 (Box-folder 17 / 3)
    - Opheim Water Department, 1964-1969 (Box-folder 17 / 4)
    - Paradise: Northwestern Improvement Company, 1939-1957 (Box-folder 17 / 5)
    - Paradise: Cuyuna Realty Company, 1957-1969 (Box-folder 17 / 6)
    - Philipsburg Water Department, 1939-1945, 1953-1969 (Box-folder 17 / 7)
    - Plains Water Department of Montana Power Company (includes rate schedule, 1916), 1939-1942 (Box-folder 17 / 8)
    - Plains: Valley Water Company, 1942-1966 (Box-folder 17 / 9)
    - Plains Water System, 1966-1969 (Box-folder 17 / 10)
    - Plentywood Water Works (includes rate schedules, 1916, 1927), 1939-1969 (Box-folder 17 / 11)
    - Plevna, Town of, 1960-1969 (Box-folder 17 / 12)
    - Polson Water Department (includes rate schedules, 1917, 1926), 1939-1969 (Box-folder 17 / 13)
    - Pony: Morris State Bank and Leah Mendenhall (includes rate schedule, 1916), 1924-1925 (Box-folder 17 / 14)
    - Poplar Water Department (includes rate schedules, 1926, 1945), 1939-1969 (Box-folder 17 / 15)
    - Red Lodge Water Department (includes rate schedule, 1926), 1939-1969 (Box-folder 17 / 16-17)
    - Rexford Water Company (includes rate schedules, 1923, 1930), 1923-1936 (Box-folder 17 / 18)
    - Rexford Fire District (includes rate schedule, 1940), 1939-1969 (Box-folder 17 / 19)
    - Ronan, City of (includes rate schedules, 1921, 1926), 1939-1969 (Box-folder 17 / 20)
    - Roundup Water Department (includes rate schedules, 1916, 1919, 1930), 1939-1969 (Box-folder 17 / 21)
    - Rudyard Water and Sewer Association / Rudyard Service and Improvement Association (includes rate schedule, 1954), 1952-1978 (Box-folder 17 / 22-23)
    - Ryegate Water System (includes rate schedule, 1921), 1939-1942, 1953-1969 (Box-folder 17 / 24)
    - Saco Water District (includes rate schedule, 1923), 1939-1969 (Box-folder 17 / 25)
    - St. Ignatius Water Works (includes rate schedule, 1940), 1941-1969 (Box-folder 18 / 1)
    - Saltese Electric Light and Water Company (includes rate schedule, 1916), 1924-1941 (Box-folder 18 / 2)
    - Saltese Electric and Water Works / Saltese Water Works, 1942-1957 (Box-folder 18 / 3)
    - Saltese Electric and Water Works / Saltese Water Works, 1942-1969 (Box-folder 18 / 3-4)
    - Sand Coulee: Nelson Coal Company (includes rate schedule, 1939), 1938-1949 (Box-folder 18 / 5)
    - Sand Coulee Water Works, 1951-1958 (Box-folder 18 / 6)
    - Sand Coulee Water Users Association, 1960-1978 (Box-folder 18 / 7)
    - Scobey Water Department (includes rate schedule, 1921), 1939-1948, 1954-1969 (Box-folder 18 / 8)
    - Seeley Lake-Missoula County Water District (includes rate schedule, 1970-1975), 1967-1975 (Box-folder 18 / 9)
    - Shelby Water Department (includes rate schedules, 1916, 1926), 1939-1948, 1952-1969 (Box-folder 18 / 10-11)
    - Sheridan Water Department (includes rate schedule, 1917), 1939-1945, 1953-1969 (Box-folder 18 / 12)
    - Sidney Water Department (includes rate schedule, 1926), 1939-1969 (Box-folder 18 / 13)
    - Somers Water Company, 1952-1969 (Box-folder 18 / 14)
    - Square Butte Water Committee (bylaws), 1966 (Box-folder 18 / 15)
    - Stanford Water Department (includes rate schedule, 1928), 1939-1969 (Box-folder 18 / 16)
    - Stevensville Municipal Water System (includes rate schedules, 1922, 1927), 1939-1969 (Box-folder 18 / 17)
    - Stockett Water Company (rate schedule and letters only), 1960 (Box-folder 18 / 18)
    - Sunburst Water Department, 1939-1969 (Box-folder 18 / 19)
    - Superior Electric Light and Water Works (includes rate schedule, 1926), 1924-1950 (Box-folder 18 / 20)
    - Superior Water Department of Montana Power Company (included in Missoula report, 1953-1962), 1952, 1961-1969 (Box-folder 18 / 21)
    - Sweetgrass Rural Special Improvement District, 1965-1978 (Box-folder 18 / 22)
    - Thompson Falls Water Department (includes rate schedule, 1917), 1939-1969 (Box-folder 18 / 23)
    - Three Forks Water Department (includes rate schedule, 1924), 1939-1946, 1952-1969 (Box-folder 18a / 1)
    - Townsend Water Department (includes rate schedule, 1916), 1939-1943, 1952-1969 (Box-folder 18a / 2)
    - Tracy Water Users Corporation, 1963-1978 (Box-folder 18a / 3-4)
    - Trout Creek: Water Service Inc., 1957-1974 (Box-folder 19 / 1)
    - Troy Water Department (includes rate schedule, 1926), 1939-1969 (Box-folder 19 / 2)
    - Twin Bridges Water Works / Water Department (includes rate schedules, 1923, 1926), 1939-1947, 1953, 1959-1969 (Box-folder 19 / 3)
    - Twodot: Big Elk Water Company (includes rate schedule, 1919), 1924-1944 (Box-folder 19 / 4)
    - Valier, Town of (includes rate schedules, 1921, 1926), 1939-1948, 1952-1969 (Box-folder 19 / 5)
    - Vaughn Cooperative Association, 1959-1978 (Box-folder 19 / 6)
    - Virginia City Water Company, 1924-1956 (Box-folder 19 / 7)
    - Virginia City Water Department, 1958-1969 (Box-folder 19 / 8)
    - Washoe: Montana Coal and Iron Company (includes rate schedule, 1933), 1933-1960 (Box-folder 19 / 9)
    - West Yellowstone: Yellowstone Water Company, 1980 (Box-folder 19 / 10)
    - Westby Water System, 1960-1969 (Box-folder 19 / 11)
    - White Sulphur Springs Water Works (includes rate schedule, 1949), 1939-1969 (Box-folder 19 / 12)
    - Whitefish Water Department (includes rate schedules, 1917, undated), 1938-1969 (Box-folder 19 / 13-14)
    - Whitehall, Town of (includes rate schedule, 1926), 1939-1969 (Box-folder 19 / 15)
    - Wibaux Water Department (includes rate schedule, 1926), 1939-1969 (Box-folder 19 / 16)
    - Winnett Water Department (includes rate schedule, 1924), 1939-1969 (Box-folder 19 / 17)
    - Wolf Point Water Department, 1939-1969 (Box-folder 19 / 18)
    - Wyola: Big Horn County Special Improvement District (includes rate schedule, 1953), 1953-1977 (Box-folder 19 / 19)
  - Special Reports
    - Butte Water Company: valuation report, 1922 (Box-folder 19 / 20)
    - Columbia Falls: "Preliminary studies and report for water system improvements", 1953 (Box-folder 19 / 21)
    - Libby Water and Electric Company: engineering report, 1922 (Box-folder 19 / 22)
    - Philipsburg: "Preliminary studies and report for water supply and distribution", 1952 (Box-folder 19 / 23)
    - Whitefish Water Department: engineering report, 1922 (Box-folder 19 / 24)
- Telegraph Companies, 1921-1959
  - Annual Reports
    - Continental Telegraph Company (affiliated with Chicago, Milwaukee, St. Paul and Pacific Railroad Company; includes rate schedules, 1937-1945), 1921, 1929-1935 (Box-folder 20 / 1-2)
    - Miles City - Jordan Wireless Company, 1921 (Box-folder 20 / 3)
    - Postal Telegraph Cable Company of Montana (includes rate schedules, 1937-1945), 1929-1943 (Box-folder 20 / 4-5)
    - Western Union Telegraph Company, 1921-1942 (Box-folder 20 / 6-16)
    - Western Union Telegraph Company, 1943-1967 (Box-folder 21 / 1-16)
    - Western Union Telegraph Company, 1968-1982 (Box-folder 21a / 1-8)
- Telephone Companies, 1914-1980
  - Annual Reports
    - Statewide: Mountain States Telephone and Telegraph Company (based in Denver, gradually acquired telephone companies around the state; many of the larger towns, such as Billings, Great Falls, and Helena, were covered by Mtn. States Tel. and Tel. throughout the period of these reports), 1915-1916, 1930-1969 (Box-folder 22 / 1-7)
    - Absarokee Telephone Company (includes rate schedule, 1926-1948; sold to Treasure State Utilities Corporation), 1924-1949 (Box-folder 22 / 8)
    - Absarokee: Treasure State Utilities Corporation (moved to Big Timber), 1950-1960 (Box-folder 22 / 9)
    - Alder: Ruby Valley Telephone Company (includes rate schedules, 1926, 1934), 1924-1940, 1944-1963 (Box-folder 22 / 10)
    - Alma: Farmers' Mutual Telephone Company of Hill County (located in Joplin, 1920-1923; includes rate schedule, 1917), 1918-1925 (Box-folder 22 / 11)
    - Antelope Telephone Company (includes rate schedule, 1926), 1914-1938 (Box-folder 22 / 12)
    - Armstead: Lemhi Telephone Company (connection to Salmon, Idaho), 1924-1979 (Box-folder 22 / 13-14)
    - Augusta Telephone Company (includes rate schedule, 1925; joined Three Rivers Telephone Co-op), 1926-1949, 1953 (Box-folder 22 / 15)
    - Augusta: Henry Bruckert (includes rate schedule, 1930), 1930-1937 (Box-folder 22 / 16)
    - Bainville: Service Telephone Company (includes rate schedule, 1925), 1925-1927 (Box-folder 22 / 17)
    - Baker: Golden Valley Telephone Company (service from Beach, S.D.; includes rate schedule, 1926), 1924-1926 (Box-folder 22 / 18)
    - Baker and Ollie: Big Hill Telephone Company (includes rate schedule, 1926), 1924-1942 (Box-folder 22 / 19)
    - Ballantine: Home Telephone Company, 1916-1923 (Box-folder 22 / 209)
    - Belfry: Clark Fork Farmers Telephone Company (sold to Treasure State Utilities Corporation, Absarokee), 1924-1950 (Box-folder 22 / 21)
    - Belgrade: Dry Creek Telephone Company, 1916-1917 (Box-folder 22 / 22)
    - Belgrade: Springhill Telephone Company, 1916-1922 (Box-folder 22 / 23)
    - Belgrade: Bozeman Pass Creek Telephone Company (includes rate schedule, 1926), 1923-1927 (Box-folder 22 / 24)
    - Belgrade: Reese Creek Telephone Company (includes rate schedule, 1926), 1933-1954 (Box-folder 22 / 25)
    - Belt to Tiger Butte Telephone Company, 1913-1923 (Box-folder 23 / 1)
    - Big Sandy: Chouteau County Telephone Company (includes rate schedules, 1920, 1926), 1924-1939 (Box-folder 23 / 2)
    - Big Sandy Telephone Exchange (includes rate schedule, 1949; sold to Triangle Telephone Association of Havre), 1940-1955 (Box-folder 23 / 3)
    - Big Timber Home Telephone Company (includes rate schedules, 1926, 1960), 1924-1961 (Box-folder 23 / 4)
    - Big Timber: Dry Creek Telephone Company, 1914, 1917 (Box-folder 23 / 5)
    - Big Timber: Otter Creek Telephone Company, 1914, 1918, 1923 (Box-folder 23 / 6)
    - Big Timber: Gibson Telephone Company (includes rate schedules, 1921, 1926), 1921-1924 (Box-folder 23 / 7)
    - Big Timber: Treasure State Utilities Company (includes Absarokee, Belfry, Browning, Chester, Ekalaka, Reed Point, St. Ignatius, etc.), 1961-1972 (Box-folder 23 / 8)
    - Big Timber: Montana Telephone Company (includes Ennis, Hysham, Harrison, Big Sky; merged into Continental Telephone Company), 1974 (Box-folder 23 / 9)
    - Big Timber: Continental Telephone Company (includes Absarokee, Belfry, Browning, Chester, Ekalaka, Reed Point, St. Ignatius, Ennis, Hysham, Harrison, Big Sky, etc.; sold to Central Montana Telephone Company), 1976-1978 (Box-folder 23 / 10)
    - Big Timber: Central Montana Telephone Company (correspondence only), 1980 (Box-folder 23 / 11)
    - Billings: Intermountain Telephone and Power Company (business phones only), 1961-1969 (Box-folder 23 / 12)
    - Broadview: Farmers Mutual Telephone Company, 1916-1923 (Box-folder 23 / 13)
    - Browning: St. Mary's International Telephone Company (includes rate schedule, 1926), 1924-1929 (Box-folder 23 / 14)
    - Browning Telephone Company (includes rate schedules, 1929-1960), 1930-1965 (Box-folder 23 / 15)
    - Buffalo: Farmers Mutual Telephone Company, 1924 (Box-folder 23 / 16)
    - Carlyle: Beaver Valley Telephone Company (includes rate schedules, 1916, 1918), 1915-1921 (Box-folder 23 / 17)
    - Carter County: West River Cooperative Telephone Company (offices and most of service in South Dakota), 1962, 1974 (Box-folder 23 / 18)
    - Charlo Telephone System (includes rate schedule, 1948; sold to Blackfoot Telephone Company, Missoula), 1949-1958 (Box-folder 23 / 19)
    - Chester: Marias River Telephone Company, 1915-1919 (Box-folder 23 / 20)
    - Chester Telephone Company (includes rate schedules, 1926-1955; sold to Treasure States Utilities Corporation, Big Timber), 1924-1965 (Box-folder 23 / 21)
    - Chinook Cleveland Telephone Company, 1915-1923 (Box-folder 23 / 22)
    - Chinook: Northfork Telephone Company, 1920 (Box-folder 23 / 23)
    - Chinook Telephone Company (includes rate schedules, 1947-1958; sold to Triangle Telephone Co-operative Association, Havre), 1926-1959 (Box-folder 23 / 24)
    - Circle: Farmers and Ranchers Telephone Company (includes rate schedules, 1926-1952), 1924-1951 (Box-folder 23 / 25)
    - Circle: Mid-Rivers Telephone Cooperative (covers McCone, Richland, Garfield, Prairie, and Dawson counties; includes rate schedule, 1952), 1952-1957 (Box-folder 23 / 26)
    - Coffee Creek: Bert J. Akerley; J. B. Leach d/b/a Coffee Creek Telephone Company (includes rate schedule, 1930), 1929-1941 (Box-folder 23 / 27)
    - Creston: East Side Telephone Company (includes rate schedule, 1926-1948; sold to Pacific Power and Light Company), 1924-1955 (Box-folder 23 / 28)
    - Culbertson: Dakota-Western Telephone Company (offices in Williston, N. D.), 1914-1917 (Box-folder 23 / 29)
    - Culbertson: South Side Co-operative Telephone Company (includes rate schedule, 1918), 1918-1924 (Box-folder 23 / 30)
    - Cut Bank Telephone Company (includes rate schedule, 1919), 1915-1919 (Box-folder 23a / 1)
    - Cut Bank: Pleasant Valley Telephone Company, 1918-1919, 1926 (Box-folder 23a / 2)
    - Dagmar Medicine Lake Telephone Company, 1923 (Box-folder 23a / 3)
    - Darby Wisdom Telephone Company (includes rate schedule, 1926), 1916, 1924-1926 (Box-folder 23a / 4)
    - Dell Telephone Company, 1920 (Box-folder 23a / 5)
    - Dillon: Southern Montana Telephone Company (includes rate schedule, 1926; service in Big Hole area, moved to Wisdom), 1923-1938 (Box-folder 23a / 6)
    - Edgar: Pryor Telephone Line (includes rate schedule, 1926), 1927 (Box-folder 23a / 7)
    - Ekalaka Telephone Company (includes rate schedules, 1926-1958), 1924-1965 (Box-folder 23a / 8-9)
    - Ennis: Bozeman Norris Telephone Company (includes rate schedules, 1939-1957; company formerly located at Norris and Pony), 1926-1955 (Box-folder 24 / 1)
    - Ennis: Madison Valley Telephone Company (company formerly located at Harrison; sold to Montana Telephone Company, Big Timber), 1957-1973 (Box-folder 24 / 2-3)
    - Eureka Telephone Company (includes rate schedule, 1926-1948), 1924-1945 (Box-folder 24 / 4)
    - Fairfield Telephone Company (includes rate schedule, 1940-1951; sold to Three Rivers Rural Telephone Cooperative), 1944-1953 (Box-folder 24 / 5)
    - Fairfield: Three Rivers Rural Telephone Cooperative (includes rate schedule, 1956; also includes service at Simms, Augusta, Fort Shaw, Power), 1957-1975 (Box-folder 24 / 6-7)
    - Fairview: Sioux Pass Farmers Exchange Company (includes rate schedules, 1926-1959; some years offices were located at Sioux Pass, 20 miles northwest of Fairview), 1918-1958 (Box-folder 24 / 8)
    - Farmington Co-operative Telephone Company, 1925 (Box-folder 24 / 9)
    - Fife-Wayne Farmers Telephone Company (includes rate schedule, 1917), 1923-1925, 1947 (Box-folder 24 / 10)
    - Fishtail: West Rosebud Cooperative Telephone Company (includes rate schedule, 1926), 1924-1926 (Box-folder 24 / 11)
    - Floweree Mutual Telephone Company, 1918-1925 (Box-folder 24 / 12)
    - Forest Grove Telephone Company (includes rate schedule, 1926; service taken over by Mountain States Telephone Company), 1926-1967 (Box-folder 24 / 13)
    - Forks: Mutual Telephone Company of Saco (formerly in Whitewater; moved to Saco and Malta), 1929-1951 (Box-folder 24 / 14)
    - Forsyth: Range Telephone Cooperative Inc. (rate schedules and correspondence), 1958-1975 (Box-folder 24 / 15)
    - Fort Benton: Benton Highwood Telephone Company (includes rate schedule, 1915), 1914-1918 (Box-folder 24 / 16)
    - Fort Benton: Pleasant Valley Farmers Telephone Company, 1919-1926 (Box-folder 24 / 17)
    - Frazer: North Star Telephone Company (includes rate schedule, 1926), 1926-1929 (Box-folder 24 / 18)
    - Froid: Farmers Telephone Company (includes rate schedule, 1926), 1924-1928 (Box-folder 24 / 19)
    - Froid Telephone Exchange (includes rate schedule, 1926), 1924-1927 (Box-folder 24 / 20)
    - Gage Telephone Company, 1934 (Box-folder 24 / 21)
    - Glasgow: Valley Rural Telephone Cooperative (includes rate schedule, 1953; map), 1956-1957 (Box-folder 24 / 22)
    - Glendive: Eastern Montana Light and Power Company (includes rate schedule, 1918), 1920-1921 (Box-folder 24 / 23)
    - Glendive: Pioneer Telephone Company (includes rate schedule, 1926), 1924-1927 (Box-folder 24 / 24)
    - Grass Range Telephone System (includes rate schedule, 1926), 1924-1959 (Box-folder 24 / 25)
    - Hall Telephone Company (includes rate schedule, 1926), 1918-1938 (Box-folder 24 / 26)
    - Harlowton: Meagher County Telephone Company (includes rate schedule, 1926), 1914-1917 (Box-folder 24 / 27)
    - Harrison-Pony Telephone Exchange (includes rate schedule, 1934), 1934-1951 (Box-folder 24 / 28)
    - Harrison: Madison Valley Telephone Company (moved to Ennis), 1952-1956 (Box-folder 24 / 29)
    - Havre: Box Elder Telephone Company (includes rate schedules, 1913-1922), 1914-1924 (Box-folder 24 / 30)
    - Havre: Northern Montana Telephone Company (includes rate schedules, 1913-1915), 1915-1916 (Box-folder 24 / 31)
    - Havre Telephone Department of the Montana Power Company (sold to Mountain States Telephone and Telegraph Company), 1915-1919 (Box-folder 24 / 32)
    - Havre: Triangle Telephone Association (includes correspondence and bylaws), 1956 (Box-folder 24 / 33-34)
    - Hilger Telephone Company (purchased from Mountain States Telephone and Telegraph Company, 1925-1926, 1934 (Box-folder 24a / 1)
    - Hingham Telephone Company (rate schedule only, 1919) (Box-folder 24a / 2)
    - Hot Springs: Flathead Mutual Telephone Company, 1924-1931 (Box-folder 24a / 3)
    - Hot Springs Telephone Company (includes rate schedule, 1934), 1932-1969 (Box-folder 24a / 4)
    - Howie Telephone Company, 1914 (Box-folder 24a / 5)
    - Hysham Independent Telephone Company (named changed to Hysham Telephone Company, 1964), 1925-1963 (Box-folder 25 / 1-2)
    - Hysham: Sarpy Mutual Telephone Company / Sarpy Farmers Rural Telephone Company, 1921, 1926 (Box-folder 25 / 3)
    - Hysham Telephone Company, 1964-1972 (Box-folder 25 / 4)
    - Intake Telephone Company (includes rate schedules, 1921-1931), 1924-1936 (Box-folder 25 / 5)
    - Inverness: Farmers Telephone Company, 1918-1924 (Box-folder 25 / 6)
    - Ismay: Earlingburt Mercantile Company / Golden Valley Telephone Company, 1913-1916 (Box-folder 25 / 7)
    - Ismay: Fulton Ranch Company (includes rate schedule, 1952, 1953-1960 (Box-folder 25 / 8)
    - Ismay Light and Telephone Company (includes rate schedules, 1926-1928; named changed to Ismay Telephone Company, 1925), 1924-1938 (Box-folder 25 / 9)
    - Joliet: Carbon County Farmers Telephone Company (includes rate schedule, 1926), 1924-1951 (Box-folder 25 / 10)
    - Joplin Telephone Company (rate schedule only), 1924 (Box-folder 25 / 11)
    - Judith Gap Telephone Company (includes rate schedule, 1939; service taken over by Mountain States Telephone and Telegraph Company), 1915-1961 (Box-folder 25 / 12)
    - Judith Gap: Western Farmers Mutual Telephone Company (includes rules for using party line, 1915), 1916 (Box-folder 25 / 13)
    - Kalispell: Northern Idaho and Montana Power Company (rates for service in Big Fork and Somers, 1913) (Box-folder 25 / 14)
    - Kalispell: Mountain States Power Company includes rate schedules, 1919-1952; merged into Pacific Power and Light Company; also includes Big Fork, Columbia Falls, Polson, Whitefish, etc.), 1931-1954 (Box-folder 25 / 15-17)
    - Kalispell: Pacific Power and Light Company (also includes Big Fork, Columbia Falls, Polson, Whitefish, etc.), 1954-1969 (Box-folder 25 / 18-19)
    - Kalispell: Niarada Telephone Company / Pine Grove and Grandview Telephone Association, 1933, 1947 (Box-folder 25 / 20)
    - Kevin Telephone Exchange (includes rate schedule, 1927), 1929-1945 (Box-folder 25 / 21)
    - Lambert: Three Buttes Co-Operative Telephone Company, 1919-1921 (Box-folder 25 / 22)
    - Lavina Mutual Telephone Company (includes rate schedule, 1926; sold to Mountain States Telephone and Telegraph Company), 1924-1959 (Box-folder 25 / 23)
    - Lewistown: East Fork Telephone Company, 1941-1952 (Box-folder 25 / 24)
    - Libby Telephone Company / Pier Telephone Company / Libby-Troy Telephone Company (includes rate schedules, 1917-1920), 1914-1923 (Box-folder 25 / 25)
    - Libby: Interstate Utilities Company (includes rate schedule, 1926; based in Spokane; also includes Troy; named changed to General Telephone Company of the Northwest), 1923-1951 (Box-folder 25 / 26-28)
    - Libby: General Telephone Company of the Northwest (includes Troy and Eureka), 1952-1969 (Box-folder 26 / 1-6)
    - Lincoln and Helena Telephone Company (includes rate schedules, 1922, 1948), 1922-1969 (Box-folder 26 / 7-8)
    - Lindsay: Farmers Mutual Telephone Company of Lindsay Montana, 1916-1925 (Box-folder 26 / 9)
    - Malta-Zortman Telephone Company (includes rate schedules, 1919-1922), 1913-1926 (Box-folder 26 / 10)
    - Manhattan: Gallatin-Madison Telephone Company, 1924-1925 (Box-folder 26 / 11)
    - Marysville: Intermountain Telephone and Electric Company (includes rate schedules, 1913-1918), 1914-1918 (Box-folder 26 / 12)
    - McLeod: Main Boulder Telephone Company, 1914, 1926 (Box-folder 26 / 13)
    - Miles City: Eastern Montana Telephone Company (includes rate schedules, 1921, 1927; sold at sheriff's sale and renamed Miles City-Broadus Telephone Company) (Box-folder 26 / 14)
    - Miles City and Eureka Telephone Company (includes rate schedule, 1926), 1924-1927 (Box-folder 26 / 15)
    - Miner Rural Telephone Company, 1918-1925 (Box-folder 26 / 16)
    - Missoula: Montana Communications, 1963-1969 (Box-folder 26 / 17)
    - Mocassin: Farmers Mutual Telephone Company (includes rate schedule, 1926), 1925-1955 (Box-folder 26 / 18)
    - Monida: Centennial Telephone Company, 1914-1916 (Box-folder 26 / 19)
    - Musselshell Telephone Exchange (includes rate schedule, 1919), 1916-1923 (Box-folder 26 / 20)
    - Ollie: Shepherd Telephone Exchange, 1923-1933, 1937 (Box-folder 26 / 21)
    - Ovando: Blackfoot Commercial Company (includes rate schedules, 1918-1922), 1918-1923 (Box-folder 26 / 22)
    - Ovando: Blackfoot Telephone Lines (includes rate schedule, 1951; name uncertain), 1918-1923 (Box-folder 26 / 23)
    - Philipsburg: Flint Creek Telephone Company (includes rate schedule, 1915), 1914-1919 (Box-folder 26 / 24)
    - Plevna: Lame Jones Telephone Company (named for creek about 18 miles SSW of Plevna), 1917 (Box-folder 26 / 25)
    - Plevna: G. E. Wilson Telephone Company (includes rate schedule, 1926), 1919-1934 (Box-folder 26 / 26)
    - Plevna Telephone Company, 1935-1945 (Box-folder 26 / 27)
    - Plevna Telephone Exchange, 1946-1954 (Box-folder 26 / 28)
    - Pony: Citizens Telephone Company (includes rate schedule, 1920; some years located in Norris; renamed Bozeman-Norris Telephone Company, moved to Ennis, 1925), 1914-1925 (Box-folder 26 / 29)
    - Pony: South Boulder Mutual Telephone Company, 1914-1918, 1926 (Box-folder 26 / 30)
    - Poplar-Nickwall Telephone Company (includes rate schedule, 1919), 1919, 1937 (Box-folder 26 / 31)
    - Potomac Telephone Company (includes rate schedule, 1922), 1917-1921 (Box-folder 26 / 32)
    - Power: Plainview Telephone Company, 1919-1924 (Box-folder 26 / 33)
    - Reed Point: White Bear Telephone Company, 1914-1918 (Box-folder 26 / 34)
    - Reed Point Mutual Telephone Company, 1916-1918, 1927-1928 (Box-folder 26 / 35)